Hey, what's up everybody?
It's about that time of the season where all of my definitive PvP guides come out for all the specs and classes that I play.
So look back on this channel and see if a guide comes out for a spec that you want to know more about.
Of course, we're going to start with Unholy, and we're actually just going to dive right into it.
So Talents is where we're starting.
I'm still doing the class fantasy naming, and you can see the Necromancer build is no more.
that is because they didn't end up buffing those talents for PvE like I thought they would.
They kind of just let them stay bad, which is a bit of a shame,
but we still have two very potent builds that we will be running this season.
Plague Doctor is disease-oriented. I'm sure you know that.
Wound Spike is clawing shadows-oriented.
And the disease package got nerfed, unfortunately.
15% all your diseases and 15% decoyal.
So I'm sure a lot of people will have to question, you know, is that build even still playable?
Well, of course it is, or I wouldn't be giving it to you.
All that did actually is just bring the Clawing Shadows and Plaguebringer talent closer together,
because before the diseases was just so much better.
So now they are close, and either one, you could pretty much say it's a toss-up, which one you want to run.
So that's why I'm going to give you both builds.
Yeah, so let's dive into it with the Plague Doctor build.
that's disease focused and if you've run watch my pvp starter guide you know that the entire top
of the tree is pretty much locked in and the bottom of the tree is actually locked in the
commander line is just terrible um it's pet focused and pet focus is just bad in pvp
because they get rooted or pseudo cc'd or kited or lost and it's really just under tuned anyway
for a pvp environment it's just too all in um focused but then the all in doesn't do anything
because they just get peeled and kited and all that stuff.
So it's just terrible.
So you go down this bottom left side,
which gives you a lot of disease modifiers and damage modifiers.
Morbidity is just overall damage.
Death Rod is overall shadow damage.
Unholy Assault is overall damage again.
Festermite is strength, which is overall damage.
I mean, you can see how this would be extremely valuable
for a class that just uses damage.
And finally, you have the thing that brings it all together.
You're going to run this in every build.
Raise a bomb.
It replaces Army of the Dead,
gives it a 1.5 minute cooldown. He applies diseases, AoE. He pulls out stealthies. He gets
you combat. He applies wounds, which are great because wounds are super buffed in PvP and also
work with necrotic wounds. So you want as much wound generation as you possibly get. And then
also he is on a 1.5 minute cooldown, which has immense synergy with the Rider Talent Apocalypse
now, which summons all four horsemen, which do a ton of damage and give you a huge wall.
So this entire Lich King army effectively comes out when you press Raise A Bomb,
and it's on such a short cooldown that it really gives you win conditions all the time.
So Raise A Bomb, completely non-negotiable.
So the only thing that changes between the two builds, honestly,
well, is of course this choice node, Plaguebringer for diseases and Clawing for the wound spike.
The other thing that I switch around is Defile.
Defile's actually really good.
It has a ton of opportunity to do damage on a point,
like in Silver Shard Mines, if you're playing Battleground Blitz,
Silver Shard Mines with the carts,
Deep Hall Ravine with the carts,
or Eots in the flag in the middle,
or just on a capture node,
Defile can start bringing out a lot of damage.
And with the Rotten Wither PvP talent,
it also has a lot of healing absorption as well,
if you get huge uptime with it.
So that's cool.
So right now with the Plague Doctor build,
you have Plaguebringer and Defile.
The whole middle avoids the mages of the dead talents
because they're just completely undertuned.
They don't do anything.
All of them, unfortunately.
So hopefully they do some tuning for that in PvE
so we can actually run them.
It gives you disease mods here and here and here.
I run Ghoulish Frenzy always
because it gives you just more damage.
I just pretty much choose every damage mod possible
because if you've played Unholy this season,
you know damage is not something you lack.
you kind of ooze it at all times, which means any damage mod that you can find,
and I picked them all right here for you, is going to be good.
There is one thing that I change out.
If I really don't think I'll get any Defile value at all, I do this.
Unholy Pact is, say it with me now, raw damage.
So every time you press Dark Transform, which is actually a nice source of damage
because it adds Unholy Blight to Dark Transform, which means it's a pretty big power window,
it will also add out Unholy Pact, which is a ton of cleave.
and if you are not getting use out of defile because you're just not fighting on a lot of
points unholy pact can do you the the big one but of course that means you would drop rotten
wither for something else and we'll talk about pvp towns very soon you're going with the entire
rider line that you always do um death charge uh pack the apocalypse um after the horseman's aid
nerf um this is just huge wall uh i end up running feast of souls because your death coils do so
much damage and you have access to so many of them but honestly both of these are really good
Fury of the Horseman just makes your horsemen out for longer, and since you get horsemen every 1.5 minutes,
you're just extending that whole crazy Lich King army go even longer.
So you could literally choose either of these, and I don't think you'd notice the difference,
because you'd be so happy with both of them.
You actually can run Sandalene with this build, or Sandalane, sorry, Sandalane with this build.
And the reason you would ever run it is very, very high cleave situations.
So again, if you are playing the Defile and you want to all-in on that Defile go,
with Rotten Wither, Defile, and Sand Lane, that's against melee cleaves in Arena,
or huge teamfights where the teamfight is all that matters in BG Blitz.
Now, unfortunately, you lose the mobility, so you have to say,
okay, this is Temple. I'm not going to go anywhere.
I'm going to fight mid the entire time, and I want to cleave as much as possible.
That's effectively the—or you're playing defense on an FC map.
Okay, I'm not chasing a Mystery Vermonk around,
because why would you ever play Sand Lane?
Then you need your mobility.
I'm just going to plant on my FC and defend them,
and I'm going to wipe everybody off of them with these crazy goes.
You can do that.
You can run Sand Lane, Defile, and Rotten Wither,
and the cleave is astronomical.
You get wounds on everybody,
and then you make sure to Defile down, Dark Transformation,
which will turn your Scored Strike into Vampiric Strike,
and you just press it every global.
Vampiric Strike, Vampiric Strike, Vampiric Strike.
You don't stop pressing it. You just keep pressing it over.
You prioritize Vampiric Strike over everything.
And the damage cleave is so crazy that if you can get everybody to be stacked up,
you would also want to switch out Vestigial Shield for A-Bomb Limb,
and we'll get to those talents soon.
You'd want to pull everybody into that pile and do that Nuclear Defile Vampiric Strike go.
That's something you can do.
So remember, what did we learn?
you can switch this out for this and you would never you would never play sand lane with this
you would always play rider because that means you're effectively saying i'm not doing cleave
goes and you'd play rider for most mobile high mobility situations high mobility maps or solo
shuffle where you're getting kited a lot or you'd swap right back you play the defile rotten wither
combo and you'd play sand lane if it is a melee cleave or you're playing defense or you're on
temple and you're just planting yourself in one spot. And that is the Plague Doctor build.
So now we're going to cut it for a moment here, you know. Now just take all that in,
take a look. It's going to be linked in the description below. Now we're going on to the
Wound Spike build. So I'm not talking about this as much because we kind of already went through
all of this. So what changes? Exactly. Clawing Shadows from Plaguebringer. Okay. And that is
a big, big single target option for ranged damage that bursts wounds and fully scales with your
mastery. So the more mastery you have, the better with this. And of course, then you're grabbing
Rotten Touch, which buffs your Clawing Shadows even further on every sudden doom, which you'll
be getting a ton of because you have Harbinger of Doom, which gives you even more access to procs.
As a result of needing this extra talent, you have to drop either the choice node of Defile
and unholy pact so instead you are just running all of this stuff pretty much locked in there's
not really a choice this is perma rider which seems silly because it's like oh well i don't
really need the mobility as much because i have this answer to being kited but sand lane and
clawing shadows don't work super well together because sand lane's vampiric strike does not
inherit the damage buff modifier from clawing shadows i don't know if that's a mistake or not
but effectively what that means is running clawing shadows and running sand lane not really that
important you would just play the plague bringer which means you would play the plague doctor right
so this is a rider build uh its mobility is insanely high and its reach its range is insanely
high so this is effectively the hey i'm playing against people who can kite i'm playing a solo
shuffle against people who can kite i'm playing a threes match against a comp that can kite
or I need to chase an FC or chase people on a BG Blitz map.
This is high mobility, high reach, very, very destructive, very hard to kite.
So very cool build.
Wound Spike build, again, everything else is exactly the same.
So take a look at the Plague Doctor build first in the timestamp,
and then you're changing to Clawing Shadows, Rotten Dutch.
Okay, now we'll look at the left side,
And we'll go back to the Plague Doctor build for that.
So you'll notice that some stuff is going to change around.
This is the build that I generally run in BG Blitz.
The sustain is still insanely high, and it has a lot of options.
It has a lot of ways to do damage, and people are rotting,
and rotting people is pretty good in BG Blitz
because it allows you to put pressure on so many targets at once.
So because this is my BG Blitz build, I switch into Death's Reach.
I don't think you need to run Death's Reach in arenas as unholy, but in BG Blitz, you need to.
Especially if you're chasing down Misfreever monks, you know how crazy their rolls are right now.
Thankfully, that's getting nerfed. More on that soon, when my Misfreever stuff comes out later.
But anyway, 10-yard extra range on Deathgrip in BG Blitz is huge.
So I run that, which means I actually have to drop some really important talents.
I can't do this.
So what I do if I'm playing arenas is, you saw it, right-click this off because you don't need sac-packed,
right-click Death's Reach because you don't need that extra range.
And then you can play Vestigial Shell and get your Blood Draw and Subduing back,
and you have these huge walls that are pretty much active all the time for Subduing
and a huge wall for Blood Draw on a proc, which just gives you a ton of extra self-healing as well
from extra Death Strikes, and then Vestigial Shell for your teammates reduces the duration
of harmful magic effects against them.
This includes CC, so this is very, very good for Arena.
But otherwise, if I have to go Death's Reach for BG Blitz, and there's also Grip of the
Dead, and Vestigial Shell, these are all options for the left side.
Everything else is locked in.
So you have things like short AMS and big Deathstrike healing and big stamina and zone for your team's survivability,
because there's a lot of casters going around like Dev and Mage and Locke.
Asphyxiate, which can be turned into Strength, but generally you run Asphyxiate as Unholy.
AoE Blind, single, or rather, double chains.
Icy Towns for more Deathcoil procs. That's non-negotiable.
This entire left side gives you the extra Strength and then gives you Null Magic,
which even though it's nerfed in PvP, it's just totally passive.
So there's always going to be value in this.
Wraith Walk for more mobility.
March of Darkness for more mobility.
I mean, you're really tough to stop as a DK right now.
Super fun.
Again, these are all the things you can play around with.
If you want D&D, if you're doing a big Defile go with Sand Lane,
what might you want with that?
Grip of the Dead.
90% movement speed slow in your go.
Wow, AoE, that's incredible.
Okay, right?
So you can play around with these things, but all of this other stuff,
fits like you can do like a little all of that is locked in um so bg talents um sand lane talent
and then survivability talents okay so now you see all that that's true with either build so i
don't have to swap to the wound spike build to show you that all over again because it's true with
both of them the other thing that'll be true with both of them is my overview on pvp talents so
let's get into that. Doom Burst did get nerfed. It still does what it used to do, which is burst
two wounds, but because the PvE version bursts a wound, then it only adds one additional wound.
That's what they made it, so it's not three wounds anymore, but you never needed it to burst three
wounds. The real problem is that bugged the PvP talent, so it can only do 45% movement speed slow,
and that's pretty lame because it itself, the doom burst extra burst is only one
because one of it comes from the sudden doom talent, right?
So now this will always only do 45% slow, which makes it a little more expendable,
but you still really want those two wounds bursted
and the slow is nice to be baked in to just your ranged spender.
So they'll probably fix that.
Either way, we still run Doomburst.
We always run Necrotic Wounds.
It's amazing in BG Blitz.
It's amazing in Arena.
It is a stackable Mortal Strike.
It's an AOE Mortal Strike.
If you have your big D&D go while you're cleaving with Scored Strike and bursting wounds on multiple players,
Necrotic Wounds is pretty much going to be an auto-pick until the talent is completely changed.
It also provides a ton of self-healing.
So why would you not want that?
This is an auto-pick.
This one is, so, auto-pick.
Doom Burst is a little worse, but we don't really have anything to choose to get rid of Doom Burst.
I mean, you can for exactly BG Blitz, but let's talk about Rotten Wither first,
because remember, Rotten Wither plus Defile or never.
Okay, so if you're running Defile and you're doing the Defile go, Rotten Wither, you can choose this.
If you're not, never choose this.
It's just exactly because Defile does a lot of damage right now.
That is the only reason Rotten Wither is good.
Okay, so here's something crazy.
Reanimation.
This is actually a BG Blood-centric thing.
It is incredibly powerful to spin
because it does AoE damage and an AoE stun.
And they kind of, since they're not killable
and not really interactable,
they will control a point,
like Blood Elf Tower on Eye of the Storm
or the Eot's main flag
or pretty much any area you need to deny,
like an Arathi base and base
that you're just trying to spin
or even Twin Peaks on defense.
It's just an AoE stun with damage
with only a runic power cost.
And we have tons of runic power gens still,
so pretty crazy, actually.
You get two of these, and it does a nice chunk of damage.
If you don't have any AoE stuns on defense,
it is just really powerful
to be able to just zombie stun people off of you.
So pretty crazy tech option there.
So you could switch that in.
And then you have a bunch of other talents.
I run Strang on stun-heavy comps in solo shuffle, so if it's like me in a DH,
DH has Fel Eruption and Chaos Nova, and I have Pet Stun and War Stun,
and my healer might even have a stun.
So having a Strang to add off of the stun is really wild and really good,
but Unholy cannot play Strang as often as Frost because it doesn't have the AA we stun that Frost has.
Okay, so all the other stuff is kind of like a never pick.
life and death has an internal cooldown. Otherwise, it'd be really good. Spellwarden is actually
really nice when you need to prevent CC on your teammates. Bargain, I don't particularly like.
I've seen some people use it. I've never once used it, and I've still had a good amount of success
in the game, so I don't think it's all that mandatory. It just gives you a shorter cooldown
on APOC, which is nice, but we have a lot of wound bursting right now, so not really that important.
the damage Crypt Fever does is kind of negligible
and it does generate
runes, which is nice, and it's a free wound
burst, so that's all the reasons
why, you just want to get that APOC a little faster
but yeah
so there are your PvP talent options
right now, I like something
like this, you can also
run this for those node maps
and then you have this for the
Defile goes, all sorts of options
super fun
so there's all of your talent combinations
um gear i talked about in my dk gear guide but now i have that gear so let's show it off
um i got my weapon from uh the quest and you can do this because ascendance is not that important
on the uh the embellishment because it stacks up slowly over a fight which is just not really that
important in pvp you'd rather have impact as soon as possible um so i was right about that one and
you can just grab your two-handed weapon from the quest for free. Then I crafted a lot of things.
I crafted down my verse to much lower than I think most people are going to do.
You can see I crafted Haste Mastery, Haste Mastery, Haste Mastery. What you should probably do if you
don't want to play it fast and loose and go all in for output stats like I do right now when I
attack the PvP dummy, I have 6-17% verse. Yeah, so obviously I know that's going to be lower than
most people are comfortable with, and that's totally fine. I've had success with it, even in
B2 Blitz, where a lot of people are doing damage to me. I'm 2800 with 3050 MMR right now.
But all you have to do to get to something you're more comfortable with, so you're not like gasping,
you're like, I can't play that low verse. It's too scary, right? If you don't want to do that,
just craft one of these rings instead of Haste Mastery, do Verse, Haste. Okay, I'll say that
one more time for you. Instead of haste mastery, do versatility and haste. That will jump your
verse up all the way to 23% or so, and that will be something you're much more comfortable with.
I did craft the proc damage embellishment, and it does just always add damage to every situation.
And Holy is a damage user, as I've said a lot of times, and that's good in BG Blitz, that's good in
shuffle that's good in arena that's good everywhere right because it's just free damage on a spec that
loves damage so i have double um focused lens embellishments and as i promised i am grabbing
just the two set and the two set pieces are leg and helmet this is because these are the two pieces
with the best stats uh haste mastery and haste verse and they don't have any crit in them you
don't do the four sets because the four set has crit and it's also nerfed in pvp uh as well as
nerfed for pve so it went down so low value that you would just never run that four set
um and thus you're only playing two allowing you to pick up every other piece to just have
your perfect stats you can see i'm going to have almost exactly no crit the only reason i have any
crit at all is because i wanted a different type of gem for the final thing as part of this gearing
section plus two movement speed per unique algari gem color i think this is really good
I'm a BG Blitz main as you saw from my rating
but I think it's good for anything
because with all of those movement speed increases
you saw we have March of Darkness and Death Charge
it's actually pretty crazy how much DK can maneuver around the map
both in BG Blitz and Arena
and it's very difficult
if you can't kite a DK that's going to be very hard for you
and this last gem really takes the cake
where you get, if you just wear all the different gem colors,
you get 10% movement speed pretty much for free
because you're going to only lose like 140 of a stat
because I just had to get that crit one
because it's the only one I could find with that color.
So I just chose all these different colors.
You can see different color, different color, or some other colors.
Color, color, color, yeah.
And it gives me 10% movement speed, and that's really nice on the DK.
I feel very fluid. I can get anywhere I need to.
I've got my Death Charger mobility as well, and I just do a crazy amount of output.
So this gearing strategy works for me.
Of course, we're running Fallen Crusader.
You have some enchants like this leg one.
I use stamina, not armor, stamina.
Of course, stamina is very good for DK.
I put first utility enchants on my rings, but you should get the bigger ones.
That helps get back some of the verse that I crafted down from the crafted pieces.
And that's everything.
that's embellishments uh the lens tier set that's only two set um the movement speed gem and the
weapon from the quest okay uh so that is effectively everything um for bg blitz on holy's role is uh
oozing damage like i've said about 70 times so that means winning team fights by just making it
unhealable cleaving a lot um you can win 1v1s on point because you have a huge wall from raise a
bomb and your self-healing is really good with ams giving you extra healing from the um osmosis
talent and your uh necrotic wounds will absorb their healing and give that back to you which is
really great and then you get extra death strike healing uh pretty much all the time from your
crazy stem buffs and uh all the stem that we have and these stem enchants and stem gems um you get
this wall like i said from pact of the apocalypse when you press raise a bomb your single target
burst is crazy, very, very difficult to deal with. So you can win 1v1s, you can play defense with
grip and chains for your teammates, you can just use damage in teamfights, and you can kill FCs
by having that same single target damage with a stackable mortal strike and multiple long-range
40-yard grips. So you can effectively be a jack-of-all-trades, and going after points is
also really good because if you cap them, you can pull out stealthies to win the 1v1 with Ray's
a bomb again you can just literally click him he'll be right next to you and you can mount up
and run around in circles and that will pull out any stealthies near you so even though you can't
choose where to put him he comes out right on top of you you can still put him without a target which
is so cool because it allows you to mount up run around in circles or death charger up run around
in circles right with raise a bomb following you and that will pull people out um in arenas uh you
do pretty much all the same things you've always done as an holy you have a stackable mortal
strike which means you want to play with a warrior a demon hunter or some caster honestly
You can play with Hunter because they have great CC and stackable Mortal Strike.
You can play with Dev because the single target damage is insane.
And you can do grip-blind AoE stun goes with his deep breath.
You can play with Assassination Rogue with AoE Mortal Strike and crazy rot damage like you have.
I really like Marksman right now, like PHDK or BM or Survival.
Honestly, PHDK really feels the best for me.
So you want to play with a Mortal Strike, lots of single target damage, good CC chains.
again stackable mortal strike single target you got it all you're very difficult to peel so if
you have kill on a go you just use trinket or lichborn or ams or ibf or death charger or grip
or any of these other tools to stop people from stopping you on what to do you also have all these
movement options that i talked about so unholy is a monster right now i know that's why it's been
nerfed now i made a video about how it was over nerfed because they didn't nerf feral or frost
mage or press or any of these other things that are not getting touched and i still believe all
that um but unfortunately i don't code the game so i have to make do with what we got here and
unholy is still in a really great spot it's just a shame some of those other classes did not get
touched um but unholy is still in a great spot uh so finally we got like some rotational stuff um
effectively it's the same as it's always been but i know people would complain if i didn't add it so
raise a bomb unholy assault dark transform apoc defile spam scorch strike coil spam sport
score strike, coil, score strike, coil, blah, blah, blah.
And you only press festering strike when you need to have two wounds on the target.
You kind of want to spend your wounds before generating them,
or you might overcap, especially during your raise A-bomb window
when he's going to be generating a lot of wounds for you.
So let me say that one more time so it's clear.
If raise A-bomb is generating wounds and infected claws,
that's a talent we should have somewhere.
There, perfect.
you rarely look at this one but it is extremely potent because it exists it applies more wounds
from your ghouls attacks and he attacks faster um during dark transform as well so that is a lot
of attack speed from all your haste and from his attack speed uh so you're just applying a ton of
wounds so you have to spend all of those wounds um before spamming festering strike because if
you're just pressing festering strike because you're like oh that's my generator and you're
not even looking at the screen, you might be at six already. Six, six, six. You're just capping
out. You're not doing anything with those wounds. Instead, you should be casting Scored Strike and
Death Coil procs to spend wounds as fast as possible. Then you see them go down to one or two,
you can reapply. But at three, four, five, six, no chance. So let's take a look at that.
So we're going to Death Charger in, raise A-bomb, Unholy Assault, Dark Transform. Let's get that
Defile down. APOC. Now we're spending. Spending. Now we're at one. We have to reapply so we can
coil. Spend. Spend. Spend. Spend. Spend. Spend. Let's take a look at the damage here. Oh, we like
that over two milli. You can see we're building up that undeath from riders again. So powerful.
Coil. Coil. Coil. Coil. Spend. Keep that Defile down as well, of course. Probably should have
100% uptime on that. I won't let it drop in this next one. We'll coil. We're still doing over
2 million DPS. This time, I don't let it drop. I immediately Defile again. Reapply my Diseases.
You can see these Diseases have never dropped, and now Defile. Perm uptime. Pressing it again.
Scourge. Scourge. Coil. Dark Transforms back up. You don't want to hold that. You press it
immediately. Then you get the four stacks for Apoc, and you blow them all up right there. That
was an Apoc burst on all four wounds. Coil, Coil, Coil. Damage is insane. There you go.
You can see that Defile third or fourth dam, but when you double that with Rotten Wither Healing Absorption, that's a lot of pressure from Defile.
That's how that Defile build ends up being so valuable.
Put it on a point or in a cleave fight.
Should be everything you need to know about Unholy.
I really hope this helps.
If you have any questions at all, let me know in the comments.
Thanks for watching.