Here we go team. We're gonna record this one live too. Had a lot of fun recording our Fury Guide live last time. Let's do another one here.
Alerts are gonna be off for this one just so you guys know.
But yeah, let's get down into it, right?
Fury, boys, is getting nerfed. Okay, we're gonna start off that way.
Fury is getting nerfed. I still think that you play the exact same build, the exact same way for Fury, and you're still gonna pump.
if you guys didn't know what's happening Thunder Asteroid is getting a 15% nerf for all warrior
specs Odin's Fury is getting a 20% damage nerf for Fury obviously although Arms is getting a
12% reduction to their auto attacks and pvp nerf reverted so Arms is saved clearly but yeah maybe
not anyway the Fury guide that I posted before I think is still good maybe just for fun I'll give
you guys just a quick look at something I might change for Fury. This is definitely not pertinent
to the Arms Guide, but just to update you guys. I think for Fury, this is the OMG Nerfs Fury build.
I don't think you need to worry about that yet. We'll talk about Fury Guide tomorrow when the
Nerfs actually come out with test things. But I think for the Fury Guide, some things that I would
change are I went out of Storm of Steel into Titanic Rage, and I like that a lot. And I think
that this is still kind of a fun combo. But that's like really one of the only things that's changed.
You can try two Armored as a Teeth or you can go into Uproar as well. That's fine. But anyway,
I don't want to get too sidetracked because I do want to talk about Arms primarily. I just wanted
to update you guys just very quickly on one thing. I think the Titanic Rage is fun because you don't
have to worry about getting enraged and you get immediately two little stacks of Whirlwinds so
you can just charge in, pop your one-shot macro and one-shot things. It's pretty fun.
But for Arms in particular, you have some cool things going on with Arms. I feel like starting
off the video already being like, hmm, ARMS is kind of mid, guys, is maybe not the best
way to do it, but it's kind of true. ARMS feels a little bit mid just because Fury feels
so good to play and the numbers are just so beautiful for Fury as well. But what's neat
about ARMS is you can do a couple cool things about it, or you can do a couple cool things
with it. And we'll start off, like we did before, with a look at the talents, okay?
So let me scoot this over here so you guys can see. The talents for ARMS Warrior, Colossus
in particular are based around the idea that Colossus has an ability called Demolish, and
as you press Mortal Strike, you get stacks of Colossal Might that will increase the damage
of Demolish. By 10%, stack up to 10 times, right? But what's cool is that Mortal Strike
and Execute grant a stack of Colossal Might, but you get it from Cleave too. But in particular,
if you go all the way down here, Colossal Might can stack up to 10 times, and if you
would gain a stack of Colossal Might and interrupt max stacks,
the cooldown of demolish is reduced by 2 seconds as well.
So, you need to keep that in mind, right?
I think it's here.
Where is it
where it actually tells you
that Critical Strikes
actually give you 2 stacks of it, right?
It's in here somewhere,
right? Here it is. Mortal Strike, Critical
Strikes grant an additional stack of Colossal
Might. So, that's something to
consider right there. MiniClaw, thanks for the subs, man.
I see you over there, bro.
Also, you need to know that Colossal Might
not only increases the damage of demolish,
and that crits give you two stacks of Colossal Knight,
that it also increases the damage of overpower by 5% per stack,
and you get Rend and Deep Wounds damage increased by 2% per stack.
So if you look at this, it's 50% increased damage of overpower,
20% increased damage on Deep Wounds and Rend when fully stacked up, right?
And then, of course, you have this huge demolish afterwards.
So that's kind of why we are going to structure our talents to buff our bleeds frequently,
make use of those buffed bleeds with Skull Splitter, and then try to stack as much Colossal
Might as we can as quickly as possible.
So that's kind of like the main idea behind the build.
So when you look at the warrior side of the talents, things look fairly similar, right,
to how Arms normally works.
You've got all these talents that do all the basic warrior stuff, intervene your stances,
your Shout, your Second Wind now, Rallying Cry, will you still like Shockwave?
I don't like Shockwave as much as I used to because now it only stuns for like two seconds in PvP,
but it's three because of this talent right here, but we'll talk about that in a second.
Thunderclap is going to be useful for applying Rend, and you come all the way down here.
Arms is interesting because I'm still taking all the points in Dragon Roar,
but because we don't need a point down here like Fury does,
we can take two out of two points and armor to the teeth which is really really nice because
that's like 3k strength right now and um it also gives you like increased amounts of strength as
time goes on yeah you also get the the extra benefit of the enemies affected by demolish
take up to 10 more damage from your uh stuff from your all damage and five percent less damage to
you. So at max stack. So yeah.
10% increased damage taken from
enemies. So like once you demolish you can keep your damage
flowing after that. But we can talk about that
in the rotation part. But yeah. So this is
basically what we're doing with this. Right? We're still getting
a good amount of utility
with Piercing Howl and Shockwave to try to help
lock people down for demolish.
But we're still getting a bunch of extra
strength. I am opting for the Haste. If you
wanted to go for the HP you could.
But nothing to affect Avatar
because this stuff is not worth.
Before we move on
there is the synergy in this build to take no dragon roar to do warlord's torment and then go
into champion spear and champion's might for extra crit and you're like whoa that would be sick
because then you're you're going to be critting hard and spoiler alert we actually like the talent
into crit or uh like a stat into crit for this build but spear continues to be bad and this
talent continues to be bad yes you can do some cool one-shot stuff with it but even then it's
not even like guaranteed to crit and you're investing two one and a half minute cooldowns
and a whole bunch of talents to still be just bad so you can try that build it is an option i don't
recommend it okay that's not what that's not what i'm recommending for this build um but here for
the arms tree you get all the stuff that you normally get as arms um all your like sort of
mandatories right um blood surge i tried it a little bit i don't think it's necessary to keep
your rage flowing.
It's really like,
there's only a couple things
that you're actually
not speccing into
the armistry.
But there's like
one flex point, right?
There's this flex point.
But there's a couple
interesting things
happening here.
So again, we're trying to
Mortal Strike as frequently
as possible,
so we actually are taking
Exhilarating Blows.
And when you combine
Exhilarating Blows,
which is a talent
that makes Mortal Strike
and Cleave technically,
but I'm not worried
about Cleave,
that's PvE stuff,
a chance to reset itself
with 20% chance.
It's pretty nice.
and then you also combine that with Battlelord,
which has a 35% chance for overpower to reset the cooldown on Mortal Strike
and generate 10 rage,
you actually end up having these situations where
you're Mortal Striking, like, a ton in a fight.
And so Mortal Strike becomes, like, your top damage,
which maybe it sometimes is anyways, but...
Like, I've had times where it's, like, Mortal Strike's resetting itself,
like, four times in a row, and you're...
Maybe, you know, a couple of those crit, right?
And then all of a sudden you're, like,
you've just demolished and you're back to max stacks,
especially if you have sweeping strikes up right and i do like improved sweeping strikes because
it makes it last six seconds longer and usually you can find one thing to cleave right and that's
pretty nice so having that combined with this and this means that you are getting a ton of extra
mortal strikes out one of the things we're not doing is buffing mortal strike a ton right
you're going to be buffing your mortal strike with overpower but it's like a tiny little buff in pvp
It's not that big of a deal. I'm not playing precision because we don't really have that much execute to stack up
Mortal strike I will do this as Slayer
We can show you the Slayer build at some point too, but it's just not doing that much for it
I still like this the execute critical strike damage is increased by 10%
Right and you have a 5% increase crit chance on execute
That's fine because you have increased crit strike damage here increased crit strike damage here and then increased crit strike damage here
So again, it's like whoa that would be insane with this warlord's torment and spear
it's like yes it would be insane if it wasn't a one and a half minute cooldown and if maybe
if Warlord's Torment still granted you Recklessness from Warbreaker maybe but it's just not but it is
a reason among other reasons to build into crit and I know that crit damage is nerfed in PvP
but you kind of double dip on crit and the reason why you kind of double dip on crit
is because, remember,
crit is giving you...
Crit Mortal Strikes is giving you
double stacks of Colossal Might.
And what does Colossal Might do?
It increases your overpower damage,
it increases your bleed damage,
and then it also increases your demolish damage.
So in a way, crit kind of ends up acting like mastery, right?
Because crit, not only...
It's fun to crit stuff, and it does big hits,
and so it kind of increases your overall DPS,
But it also increases the damage you're dealing through just percent damage increases, right?
So it kind of like double dips like mastery.
It's kind of neat how that works.
So additionally, you're also playing unhinged for more mortal strikes, sweeping strikes, blade storm.
You're going to be unhinging and hitting lots of targets with mortal strikes,
so you can build up your stacks really, really fast.
And then, again, some of these talents are sort of mandatory.
You're going to see pretty much these taken every arms build,
like all these defensive thingies
or Breaker or Claws of Smash.
Anger Management.
I've messed around with Spiteful Serenity and Test of Might
a little bit. I'm not super impressed. Maybe there's
some place for that, but I don't think
it's better. I think that just the
general overpower damage increase is better
than the cleave for most situations of PvP.
But yeah, so this talent right here
is kind of flexed. So if you really wanted to do
Fatality, you could.
If you wanted to put it into Massacre,
you could. If you feel
like you are rage starved you can chuck it in blood surge but i think overall skull splitter
just ends up being an okay button to press if you don't mind having an extra button to press
because you are going to be getting big bleed buffs from your colossal might stacks you're
going to be getting big bleed buffs from a frequent you know usage of dragon roar thunderous
roar that is and so i feel like as a result your your warbreaker into thunderous roar aoe that you
can do relatively reliably into a skull splitter, especially if it's a sweeping strike, skull
splitter is going to make two targets bleed really hard, which is kind of cool.
But going through the hero talents, again, we know what demolish does.
You have martial expert.
These aren't really choices, but it's just kind of good to understand what the build
is.
For the choices that you have, you can either have shockwave knock enemies up in the air,
which is kind of cool because it acts like they're shockwaved and knocks them up.
So, like, potentially there's, like, some CC there if they're DR'd.
I don't think I like this one that much.
The cooldown reduction is kind of cool, but I think I'd rather just have one extra second on Shockwave.
I'm taking the overall bleed damage increase rather than the Shockwave Cleave Whirlwind thing.
That's absolutely got to be PvE right there.
At this point, I'm experimenting with the Ignore Pain thing.
I kind of like the Veteran Vitality thing, though.
I think it's kind of cool, but I think I liked it more when I had a chance to proc it rather than only the low health thing.
So this is like a little bit more standard like HPS, rather this is like burst HPS at low situation.
So either one's fine, I guess, but Ignore Pain's probably a little bit more reliable.
Just increase damage.
This is the cool one that makes us want to play crit.
This is cool too.
I think they nerfed the size part of that, but no, they didn't.
But you just deal more damage, take less damage.
And then of course the dominance where you actually get a debuff on enemies from that so when it comes to stats
I know we already teased this quite a bit. I'm actually recommending to go to a
Arms crit haste setup right so go crit helm crit neck crit shoulders crit cloak haste
Chest piece and again if you understand how this works every piece of PvP gear has versatility on it
So then you have your choice of two stats, so you take crit when you can get it and then haste when you can
We're going really low on mastery, but again, we're kind of double dipping.
You could do crit mastery too if you wanted to, but I feel like haste kind of works well
with what we're trying to do, which is mostly build stacks.
Right?
But you could go mastery if you wanted to.
But we have haste vs. chest, haste vs. bracers, crit gloves, haste belt, haste legs, crit
boots, haste ring, crit ring, proc trinket, and just, you know, get out a CC trinket.
You could use the Burst Trinket if you wanted to.
And then we have a Haste-Vurse weapon.
So that's going to put us at about 21% crit, 13% haste, 11% mastery.
So the mastery, again, is looking a little low, but it is what it is.
In terms of...
Oh, and then I guess your enchants, again, are going to be like strength on your chest.
I would say speed on your cloak and braces, which I haven't done yet.
And then just probably versatility on your rings.
Unless you just wanted to do more crit, which I think is fine if you wanted to.
But in terms of your rotation, let's see, there's a couple macros. You don't need a million macros.
A couple of these macros are going to look very similar to the ones I gave you for Fury.
But in general, I think there's like two macros, right?
You can press Avatar separately. I think it's a good idea.
But if you wanted to put it all together, it'll be a Battle Stance, Colossus Smash, Sharpened Blade,
cancel your Bladestorm, Avatar, and use your Onyx Trinket, which is just going to be your standard warbreaker thing.
I think it's good frequently to have Avatar separate from Warbreaker so that you can press Avatar to get out of a root.
You don't want to use that as Fury because you're Odin's Furying and just air if you do it that way.
But this way, you guys can hear the Minecraft hype in the background.
You are just using it all together, which is fine.
But with Arms, you don't really have anything that Avatar does besides press Avatar.
So you can bind it separately.
Recommend that you do that.
There's another one for...
For, this is kind of an interesting macro, where it's a demolish and a colossal smash cast sequence.
That's kind of fun if you really want to save buttons.
I don't really prefer that, though.
But it is kind of neat.
And you can just do a cast sequence, reset equals 20, colossal smash, comma, demolish.
Where it's still sharpened blades, avatar is easier to drink it, puts you in battle stance, that kind of thing.
That's, I'm trying to think of other kind of lazy macros that you guys might like.
This is another lazy one.
Again, a lot of these macros are kind of situations where I don't necessarily recommend it, but if you don't mind being a little bit lazy, you're trading convenience for precision.
You can put ignore pain in your overpower button because overpower doesn't cost rage.
And so whenever you press overpower, like every 12 seconds, it'll cast ignore pain for you.
This is like if you struggle with not pressing ignore pain enough, like you just kind of forget to do it.
This is a button that can help you do that, right?
just slash cast overpower, slash cast ignore pain, and cancel your blades from if you need to.
But a lot of these macros will be things that you can find on the Fury video as well.
And like Victory Rush, I think it's kind of nice to cast ignore pain with Victory Rush.
I have in Die by the Sword, I have Die by the Sword casting putting me in defensive stance if I'm not in defensive stance.
And it'll also cast ignore pain as well.
You can put ignore pain in any macro because it's off global cooldown, right?
Sometimes it's even a good idea to put ignore pain in your blades for macro
because Bladestorm doesn't cost rage, but it's going to generate a lot of rage for you.
So if you go into a Bladestorm rage capped, it's kind of like wasting rage.
And if you want to ignore pain before the Bladestorm, I think it's kind of a good idea.
So yeah, there's all kinds of stuff going on in the background,
but hopefully you guys still get in the deets.
All right, so armed with those basics in mind,
your rotation is going to probably look a little something like this.
You're going to sweeping strikes before you go in.
You're going to charge in.
You're going to press your Warbreaker avatar thing.
You can hit him with a little sweeping strikes. You can thunderclap him. You can hit him with a skull splitter.
And I would say you probably want to, well you also want to Dragon Roar.
You're going to want to continue to Mortal Strike as long as you can.
Once you're out of overpowers and you're out of Mortal Strikes, that was a good time to Bladestorm.
And when you come out of the Bladestorm, probably could Shockwave if you need to and then Demolish.
Boom. And then out of that, you just keep on pumping.
So the one thing with that burst that I didn't do right off the rip is Dragon Roar. Right?
So Dragon Roar as soon as you get in there so you get your buffs all amped.
If you wanted to you could wait to Dragon Roar until you're ready to Skull Splitter.
But yeah Skull Splitter, Sweeping Strikes is kind of one of the main things you're going
to be doing to do the AoE cleave right?
And then as you kind of just get into your rotation hopefully we can get a couple Mortal
Strike resets off of its own self.
So you're getting Mortal Strike resets here.
So you press it three times in a row.
Demolish is already ready again.
So you could just let that rip.
one of the things that I
am kind of thinking for my own self
as I'm going through the rotation here
is like, do I want to save
demolish stacks
to like do more damage
with overpower? And I've
sort of thought about that.
As I go on more, and as I'm like
just doing BGs and stuff,
I think it's better to just let it rip.
The cool thing about demolish an arena though
is like, if you have the threat
of demolish constantly hanging over your
opponent's heads, then they may
use cooldowns in kind of like a suboptimal
way, right? Like if every stormbolt
they're terrified of demolish, then
they might just trinket a stormbolt
that you actually, that they don't really
need to trinket, right? And then you can
make them overuse defensive cooldowns
every stun or every time that
they've got a... Hey, Sam?
I'm working here, bro.
He does. He knows that I record a video.
I know.
I know. So, they could end up overusing cooldowns.
So here again, dragon right here, skull splitter.
They could end up overusing cooldowns because the threat of this demolish is hanging over their head.
But as I go through and actually just play the game,
it feels like you really just want to press demolish whenever you can,
just for the pressure purpose of keeping it rolling.
And this build ideally is designed to get your demolish like off cooldown quickly,
but also have the stacks up quickly too, right?
So I don't think that you need to hold Demolish.
That's kind of where I'm at right now.
I don't think I need to hold on to Demolish.
I think you just let it rip.
So again, we don't have Avatar,
but how it will work is, again,
you press Sweeping Strikes before you charge in on something.
I mean, obviously, if it's only single target,
you don't need Sweeping Strikes.
But charge in, Warbreaker, Dragon Roar,
probably hit Immortal Strike just as you can,
Skull Splitter and Bladestorm.
Come out of the Bladestorm.
Demolish likely will be stacked up at this point.
You still might want to hit a Mortal Strike just because
hitting Mortal Strike on cooldown
is just a good idea, right?
This is a good idea. You're just going to get damage
out that way. You can kind of farm
for procs. You can farm your anger management a little
bit, right? Just a good idea
to do that. And then Skull Splitter, you know,
whenever it's off CD and you got...
It doesn't really matter. You just have to
have a fresh set of bleeds for Skull Splitter.
I would love for them to bring that version of skull splitter back where it actually did all the bleeds all at once
But it doesn't really matter as long as you just hit a skull splitter
The cool thing about skull splitter is you can do it on two targets right you can sweeping strike skull splitter. That's kind of nice
I will say as I'm going through my rotation here if you were like dude
I hate skull splitter, and I'm noticing I'm a little bit low on rage
The adjustment to make is really simple right you just take skull splitter out
and you put it in literally anything else that you want, but I think that
Blood Surge actually feels kind of good for just like consistent, like plenty of
rage for Ignore Pain, plenty of rage for just spamming those Mortal Strikes as
they keep proccing, and that'll be good to go. And so with talents, gear, macros,
and general rotation gameplay discussed, what other questions do you guys have?
Specifically about arms. Like we will be linking the talent profile for you, yeah.
We will and I still think that fury is gonna be better cat me on background. Yeah, it's Samson
He thinks he's an outside cat. He just wants to live outside
He's naughty, but yeah, so you guys have any questions about arms in particular. How come I don't like fatality
I don't think it does enough damage. I'll think doesn't have damage, but you can you can put fatality in there
there's definitely some nasty combo potential for you know doing your you're doing your burst rotation and
You know you hit somebody with a demolish
they're at very low health with a demolish and you you're playing kind of like a 20 health execute
they come out of it and they just get slashed i just don't think it's that good it's a very
specific situation finishing power is cool though so that's one of the places where you can put that
flex talent if you like fatality finishing power is good right wrecking throw shattering throw what
would you swap out for it i mean realistically you could probably pop a point out of armor to
the teeth if you need that utility that bad i would take that i think your flex point is this
second point of armor to the teeth.
Or you could take it out of uproar, but I think, I don't
know. I feel like it's either uproar
or armor to the teeth. Just pop that
point out, because everything else kind of makes it
all collapse. Right?
Colossus or Slayer? This guide is for Colossus.
I think Colossus is a little bit more interesting.
I think Slayer is pretty straightforward.
We could make a guide for that, too.
But, yeah. I feel like Slayer
Slayer is just kind of, like,
a little bit more standard, just a little bit more
pumpy. With this one, you're playing crit.
there's all this kind of like interesting stuff going on with it right I guess one thing with
skull splitters you want to make sure you get thunderclap out before you skull split doesn't
really matter that much having demolish is kind of fun it also makes it very frustrating right
where with demolish is like misses or people just walk away from you while you're sitting
there channeling it right they're in a piercing howl and you just kind of they just slowly walk
away you know it's kind of annoying but I think that with demolish and this with the crit thing
it makes the spec a little bit more interesting right giving up howl be worth yeah I mean like
Use your intuition on it.
If you don't need Piercing Howl, then take it out.
As long as you understand what points are ones that you can flex for other utility, absolutely.
If you don't need the slow, but you want a bigger stun and shorter cooldown on the stun, then sure.
It's like fighting a melee cleave.
You can even do Crackling Thunder as this build if you wanted to.
If you don't need a super slow, you just want to have...
This is another melee cleave option, right?
You could even do this for melee cleave, right?
You can do all kinds of stuff, but these are the points that you can flex and yeah
Just knowing knowing which points are available to you to flex or is good. Yeah
You guys feel like you got a pretty good a pretty good feel of this
Say that fury where is still better arms currently absolutely
I think it will be after the after the nerfs too
But if you want to play arms you have some options and for those those people out there who are like you know I want
To try out
Colossus what would be a good spec and a good way to set up my character to play colossus arms
I think it's going to be a situation like this where it's
stacking crit and haste and hammering with mortal strike resets basically.
It's kind of what I have in mind. It's kind of the way that the build makes
sense to me. It's trying to stack up a ton of colossal might as quickly as
possible and using colossus as like a like a pressure and momentum class.
Because I mean in BGs, a fury is still absolutely dunking but colossus has its
moments where it can kind of do
Fury-esque damage
in these long extended fights.
And again, if you're finding yourself Rage Starved, you can go
Blood Surge,
or you can go ahead and just take
the
Ignore Pain
macro out, but I think that you're going to have plenty of rage
in a PVE encounter.
Just use normal overpower.
You're going to have plenty.
But yeah, it's an interesting build, and so I wanted to share it with you guys
because I think that there's potential here.
there's potential there's potential all right I still prefer slayer fury over
everything but I think that'll get you guys started on an arms build if you
guys like it well of course we'll we'll drop this in the chat for you we'll put
it in the YouTube video for you along with some of the macros and hopefully
this will get you guys started and get you situated on an arms PvP build and
then over time as arms gets buffed or whatever we will continue to update this
but I just wanted to get you guys squared away for arms PvP build just to
get you started because arms is still pretty fun there is some cool stuff and if we really dig
um colossus then this video and this build can be one that you can try out anyway let me know
what you think and if you guys have any questions feel free to swing by the stream we're like
streaming a ton these days we always do but um it continues to be a blast to check things out
and experiment as we go either way thanks for watching make sure you show the video some love
and come hang out with us on twitch as well peace